

Darussalam, Mirpur-1, Dhaka 1216. Email: arshoheb23@gmail.com Cell phone: 016 80 232 149



Talented and Attentive professional as well as research oriented with a Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Electronic Engineering having concentration on Electronics and Renewable energy systems, currently pursuing EMBA from BRAC University. A dynamic, team spirited, highly selfmotivated with an extraordinary blend of leadership quality has made my previous projects and researches efficacious and documented mvself for professionalism, positive mental attitude. commitment excellence and demonstrated ability to communicate with senior colleagues, management associates. Creative problems solving , analytical model designing and specifications has lead me to have an advance knowledge on MATLAB simulation, Proteus circuit simulation, ADVISOR, AutoCAD and some others simulation and language software's which made my engineering works inimitable in each time. Research and project experience with different professors and managing other engineering groups activity has made me able to handle multiple projects, understand the actual environment and meet deadlines under pressure.

Area of Interest

- Teaching
- Research and Development works
- Renewable energy (Design and implementation of projects).
- Vehicular Technologies (Automobile engineering and Mechanical Designing)
- Electronic designing
- Motivational Speech

Ataur Rahman

Lecturer, Engineer and Researcher

----- Career Objective -----

To utilize my technical skills for achieving the target and developing the best performance in the organization. I would like to implement my innovative ideas, skills and creativity for accomplishing the developments.

----- Employment History ------

✓ SENIOR FACULTY (Continuing)

ACADEMIA ENGLISH MEDIUM SCHOOL

Campus Location: 88, Gausul Azam Avenue, Sector: 13 Uttara, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Department: Mathematics and Science

Duties/Responsibilities:

- >Managing the department of Mathematics and Science.
- >Delivering lectures using appropriate and innovative teaching strategies.
- >Delivering online lectures using Zoom, Google Meet and manages Google Classroom
- >Developed curricula, lesson plans, and instruction in core subject areas.
- >Administrative work.
- >Student counseling and supervising curricular and co-curricular projects and activities.
- >Delivering speeches in various seminars and conferences.
- >Attending and conducting meetings with parents and teachers
- >Conducting the training program for teachers.

✓ Project Engineer (19 November, 2017 – 19 November, 2018)

BRAC UNIVERSITY

Company Location: 45 Mohakhali, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Department: EEE

Duties/Responsibilities:

- >Supervising Student's Thesis work.
- >Administrative work (Maintain the CARC financial records, Maintaining Company's Accounts, EEE/ECE Accreditation and maintain co-ordination and communication of CARC with outside collaborators and clients).
- >Student Counseling.
- >Delivering speeches in various seminars and conferences.
- >Attending Meetings.

Major Projects

- •Designed and implemented electrically assisted Torque sensor based Human Hauler, Ambulance Van and Cargo Hauler during Research work.
- •Implemented Solar Battery Charging Station during Research work.
- •Designed and implemented electrically assisted Torque sensor based Wheelchair during Research work.
- •Designed and implemented Solar Cold Storage during Research work by conducting full thesis work with Load test, No-load test, Quality analysis, Battery test, Temperature test and commissioning the whole project with 800W Solar panel set.
- •Implemented Solar Stove with Double burner during Research work.
- •Designed and Implemented Dark sensor using OPAMP in Digital Logic Design Course.
- •Designed 4-bit ALU system in VLSI course.
- •Made temperature box based on US Army academy paper in Control System course.
- •Designed and implemented Automatic Gas Stove on Digital System Design course.
- •Prepared audio sampling code on Digital signal processing course.
- •Monitored thesis projects on the topic: Micro-controller based Torque sensor adjuster circuit.

----- Employment History (Continued) -----

✓ Project Engineer (01 October, 2016 – 30 June, 2017)

BRAC UNIVERSITY

Company Location: 45 Mohakhali, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Department: EEE

Duties/Responsibilities:

- >Supervising Student's Thesis work.
- >Administrative work
- >Delivering speeches in various seminars and conferences.
- >Attending Meetings.

✓ Research Engineer (01 September, 2015 – 31 August, 2016)

BRAC UNIVERSITY

Company Location: 45 Mohakhali, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Department: EEE

Duties/Responsibilities:

- >Research Projects and responsibilities:
- Design, develop and implement renewable energy (solar energy) technology based application projects.
- Conducted and supervised 1 yearlong IDCOL (Infrastructure Development Company Limited) funded pilot project on "Solar Assisted Electric Tri-wheeled Vehicles with Torque Sensor Technology" in collaboration with BRAC HNPP.
- > Student Counseling.

----- Educational Information -----

Executive Masters of Business Administration, EMBA (2020)

Summer 2020

BRAC University, Bangladesh

Bachelor in Science in Electronic and Electrical Engineering (2015)

Major Concentration: Electronics

CGPA 3.13 out of 4 scale BRAC University, Bangladesh

Advanced level (2011)

Grades: 1A, 2B

Concentration: Science (Mathematics, Physics and Chemistry AS)

British Council

Ordinary level (2009)

Grades: 1A, 3B, 1C

Concentration: Science (Bengali, Mathematics B, Pure Mathematics, Physics and Chemistry)

British Council

Computer skills

•Programming language: JAVA.

•Simulation and Design Tools:

MATLAB, Mathematica 6, Solid Works, Google Sketchup, Blender, Pspice, Proteus, Export Dsh2, Microwind, AutoCAD.

•Photo Editing Tools: ADOBE Illustrator, ADOBE Photoshop, ADOBE Dreamweaver.

•Document Management Software: Microsoft Office, LATEX.

•Operating Systems: Microsoft Windows, Ubuntu.

Key Courses

- •VLSI Design
- Analog Integrated Circuit Design
- •Digital System Design
- Optoelectronics
- •Digital signal processing
- •Control System
- •Semiconductor Devices and Materials.
- •Independent Research Study on Renewable (Solar)System

Strengths

- •Leadership
- •Confidence in public speaking
- •Experienced in customer service
- •Willingness to take challenges
- •Able to do work in team environment

----- Publications ------

 Journal publication: MD Jaber AL Rashid, Ataur Rahman and A. K. M Abdul Malek Azad, "Electrification in Rural Bangladesh Using Solar Home System: Progress, Problems and Prospect", ResearchGate Publisher, International Journal of Energy, Information and Communications (IJEIC), 2017.

Published in ResearchGate:

https://www.researchgate.net/publication/319125355 Electrification in Rural Bangladesh Using Solar Home System Progress Problems and Prospect?fbclid =IwAR3mQxVZMBzViNUxLAsPOmFmkh0VmaVFqELQAGEhQbt5xKl_DDsaaEZEeOg

Journal publication: MD Jaber AL Rashid, Ataur Rahman, Abu Raihan Mohammad Siddique and A. K. M Abdul Malek Azad, "A Novel Approach of Improving Battery Performance and Longevity of the Developed Electrically Assisted Tri-Wheeler Vehicle by Implementing Torque Sensor Technology", Hindawi Publisher, International Journal of Vehicular Technology (IJVT), 2017. Published in Hindawi:

https://www.hindawi.com/journals/ijvt/2017/3757421

O Conference publication: F.R.Khan, A.T.Aurony, A.Rahman, F.Munira, N.Halim, A.Azad, "Torque Sensor Based Electrically Assisted Hybrid Rickshaw-Van with PV Assistance, and Solar Battery Charging Station," The paper has been accepted for presentation and publication at 3rd International Conference on Advances in Electrical Engineering (ICAEE) to be held on 17-19 December 2015, IUB Campus, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Published in IEEE Explore:

 $\underline{http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?arnumber=7506851\&filter\%3DAND(\underline{p_IS_Number\%3A7506780})\%26pageNumber\%3D3}$

 Multinational Mass Media and Information firm- Thomson Reuters Publication: "Cheap solar ambulances to speed into service in rural Bangladesh"

Available at:

http://news.trust.org/item/20170214110125-vmv7z/

O Newspaper- The Daily Observer publication: "Solar in Wheelchair".

Available at:

http://www.observerbd.com/2016/01/16/131230.php

 Newspaper Publication- Dhaka Tribune: "Powered wheelchair developed by BRACU students", Available at:

 $\underline{\text{http://archive.dhakatribune.com/arts-culture/2016/jan/05/powered-wheelchair-developed-bracu-students}$

O Newspaper Publication- The Daily Star: "Improvised, new look 3-wheelers in the making" Available at:

http://www.thedailystar.net/frontpage/improvised-new-look-3-wheelers-the-making-1301812

Newspaper publication- Dhaka Tribune: "Powered by the sun".

Available at: https://issuu.com/dhakatribune/docs/160921191907-fb225561349846c09ebc9a8758afa2bb/19?e=6924309/38991726

০ Newspaper publication- Kaler Kantho: " বাঁচাবে মায়ের প্রাণ".

Available at:

http://www.kalerkantho.com/feature/campus/2016/09/07/402696

Languages

- •English (Expert)
- •Bengali (Expert)
- •Hindi (Primary)
- •Chinese (Primary)

Extra Curriculum Activities

- •TARC (Training and Resource Centre) from BRAC University
- •Volunteered in Asia cup 2012 under Bangladesh Cricket Board
- •Admin of EduWorld Tuition Provider (Providing Student tutors)
- •Managing Online Shopping Website
- •Managing a Multi Cuisine Restaurant
- •Student Tutoring
- •Student Counseling
- •Debate Competition
- •Volunteering and Community Service

----- Personal Information -----

Father's Name : Late Azizur Rahman

Mother's Name : Parvin Rahman

Date of Birth : December 23, 1993

Gender : Male

Nationality : Bangladeshi

Religion : Islam

Permanent Address : 36 B/B, 2nd Colony, Mirpur-1,

Darussalam, Mazar Road, Dhaka.

Phone : 016 80 232 149, 02 90 123 86

Current Location : Dhaka

----- Referees -----

Name : Engr. Kazi Istiaque Hasan

Organization : Power Grid Company of Bangladesh Ltd
Designation : Superintending Engineer, Project Director

Address : NLDC Bhaban, Aftabnagar, Dhaka-1212, Bangladesh.

Contact Number : 017 140 99 363, 02 9888 980

Email Address : pd-ab@pgcb.org.bd

Name : Dr. AKM Abdul Malek Azad, PhD

Organization : BRAC University

Designation : Professor, EEE, IEEE Head, CARC Director Address : 66 Mohakhali, Dhaka- 1212, Bangladesh

Contact Number : 015 51 030 627, 096 744 5131

Email Address : a.azad@bracu.ac.bd